{
  "year": 2017,
  "mcq": [
    {
      "prompt": "Which of the following is an infringement of the Copyright Act?",
      "optionA": "The contractor makes copies of your construction drawings to issue to the sub-contractors.",
      "optionB": "Your client paid you for design services rendered and sold the land to another developer. The new developer uses your design to construct.",
      "optionC": "Your staff makes copies of the firm's drawings and shows it to another party.",
      "optionD": "You publish a completed project in a magazine without seeking your client's permission",
      "answer": "C",
      "explanation": "Refer to Copyright Act and also succinct excerpt from GuideMeSingapore Hawksford. \n a) Not true. Owner making copies in relation to works. Refer to CL 35. \n b) Not true. Client having paid for the design services is now the owner of the design copyright. Refer to CL 72. \n c) True. \n d) Not true."
    },
    {
      "prompt": "National Parks has guidelines for the conservation of trees. Which of the following is / are true?",
      "optionA": "Tree protective fencing / hoarding, which protects the trees from construction activities, is ONLY applicable within the development site.",
      "optionB": "No dumping of debris, excavated materials and / or storage of construction materials and equipment are allowed within the Tree Protection Zone",
      "optionC": "Written approval must be obtained from the Commissioner of Parks & Recreation for the cutting or removal of any tree exceeding 1.0m girth ONLY within the Heritage Road Green buffer.",
      "optionD": "No written approval required for the cutting or removal of trees within a landed house development.",
      "answer": "B",
      "explanation": "GUIDELINES ON GREENERY PROVISION AND TREE CONSERVATION FOR DEVELOPMENTS 2018 \n a) not true, applicable to road side trees. Refer to clause 2, pg26 tree conservation, pg 14 vacant land, green buffer p15 \n b) true, clause 2 \n c) not true , refer to clause 2 p26, pg 11 tree conservation, p14 vacant land, green buffer p15 \n d) not true, Cl 7.1.1 written approval is required."
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Which of the following new developments requires a submission of Walking and Cycling Plan to URA?",
      "optionA": "A retail development with GFA of 8,000 m2.",
      "optionB": "An office development with GFA of 15,000 m2.",
      "optionC": "A secondary school with 1,500 students.",
      "optionD": "An international school with 2,500 students.",
      "answer": "D",
      "explanation": "Answer found in URA circular dated 7 Dec 2018"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Vehicular access locations for landed terrace housing developments should be paired adequately spaced apart. What is the minimum distance between each pair?",
      "optionA": "4 metres.",
      "optionB": "5 metres.",
      "optionC": "6 metres.",
      "optionD": "8 metres.",
      "answer": "C",
      "explanation": "\"Refer to LTAâ€™s Code of Practice - Street Work Proposals Relating to Development Works (Version 1.2) Chapter 4, Clause 4.4\""
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Your client has held back your professional fee although you have fulfilled all your duties for a completed building project. You would like to apply for adjudication under the Building and Construction Industry Security of Payment Act (SOPA).",
      "optionA": "This is possible as long as both parties are Singapore registered companies, regardless of the location of the project site.",
      "optionB": "This is possible as you have made a payment claim and the client has not made a payment response by the due date.",
      "optionC": "This is not possible as SOPA is only applicable to construction works and not applicable to consultancy services.",
      "optionD": "This is not possible as the outstanding fee is less than $10,000.",
      "answer": "B",
      "explanation": "SOP Act \n a) not true, Does not apply to project outside singapore. refer to clause 4 p9. \n b) true \n c) not true, SOPA applicable to architectural services. Refer to clause 3(1) \n d) not true, no minimum outstanding fee. refer to clause 24 p34."
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Chemical dry powder fire extinguishers are generally effective for \n i) Class A Fire. \n ii) Class B Fire. \n iii) Class C Fire. \n iv) Class D Fire.",
      "optionA": "i & ii",
      "optionB": "i, ii & iii",
      "optionC": "i, ii & iv",
      "optionD": "All of the above",
      "answer": "D",
      "explanation": "Singapore Standard 578-2019 \n Refer to Cl 8.2.2, CL 8.2.3, CL 8.2.4 and CL 8.2.8 p15-16"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the Architects Act, which of the following is true?",
      "optionA": "A foreign architect who is registered and practising in Singapore is not subjected to the jurisdictions of the Act.",
      "optionB": "Whilst the Board of Architects has disapproved an architectural competition, firms are still allowed to take part as it is within their own interest.",
      "optionC": "As a registered architect, you will not endorse any drawings for submission that a friend has prepared unless you have personally scrutinised and checked the drawings.",
      "optionD": "When invited as a speaker of a conference, an architect cannot receive remuneration for his services rendered.",
      "answer": "C",
      "explanation": "Architect's Acts and Progessional code of conduct and ethics \n a) not true. Foreign architects registerd and practising in Singapore are subjected to the juridiction of the act. CL 15(2b) Architect Acts \n b) not true, architect shall not take part in architectural competition where board has issued a warning. professional code of conduct and ethics section 10(1) \n c) True, architect's act refer to (2) \n d) not true, is not out line in the architect's act. It is outline in professional code of conduct and ethic. 1(b)."
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the pollution control requirements, which of the following is / are true? \n i) The drain-off of a cooling tower shall be discharged into a public sewer. \n ii) Wastewater generated from a chemical analysis laboratory shall be discharged into a sewer via a dilution tank. \n iii) Diluting trade effluent with industrial water to comply with the allowable limits is permitted. \n iv) Wastewater generated from a food analysis laboratory shall be discharged directly into a sewer.",
      "optionA": "i & ii",
      "optionB": "i & iii",
      "optionC": "i, ii & iv",
      "optionD": "All of the above",
      "answer": "C",
      "explanation": "NEA Pollution Control \n i) True, CL 4.1.2(b) \n ii) True CL 4.1.2 (g) \n iii) Not true. Trade effluent should not be diluted with industrial water. CL 4.1.2 (a) \n iv) True Cl 4.1.2 (g)"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Which of the following will offer GFA incentive / exemption? \n i) Integration of spa and gym on rooftop gardens in a new Orchard Road development under Landscaping for Urban Spaces and High-Rises (LUSH) 2.0 Programme. \n ii) As one of the conditions to enjoy balcony bonus GFA, a proposed condominium development has to incorporate a minimum 65% of Prefabricated Bathroom Units (PBUs). \n iii) Night lighting of a commercial building in the CBD in accordance to URA Night Lighting Masterplan guidelines. \n iv) The integration of a covered plaza space on level one of a commercial development fronting a major street and open at all times under the URA Privately Owned Public Spaces (POPS)",
      "optionA": "i & ii",
      "optionB": "i & iii",
      "optionC": "i, ii & iii",
      "optionD": "All of the above",
      "answer": "D",
      "explanation": "URA guideline and circular \n i) True \n ii) True based on the old code. New balcony circular DC18-07 17oct2017, 80% of min. PBU are to be incorporated. \n iii) True, DC19-05 urban design guideline for devt within downtown core 27mar2019 \n iv) True"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "The doorway of a one-way swing door shall have manoeuvring spaces on both sides for wheelchairs. Which of the following are true? \n i) On the pull side, a minimum space of 450mm adjacent to the edge of the door with a minimum clear floor space of 1200mm wide by 1200mm deep. \n ii) On the pull side a minimum space of 600mm adjacent to the edge of the door with a minimum clear floor space of 1500mm wide by 1500mm deep. \n iii) On the push side, a minimum space of 300mm adjacent to the edge of the door with a minimum clear floor space of 1200mm wide by 1200mm deep. \n iv) On the push side, a minimum of 600mm adjacent to the edge of the door with a minimum clear floor space of 1350mm wide by 1500mm deep.",
      "optionA": "i & ii",
      "optionB": "i & iii",
      "optionC": "ii & iii",
      "optionD": "ii & iv",
      "answer": "C",
      "explanation": "BCA Accessibility Code \n i) not true \n ii) true, Cl 4.4.6.1 p60 \n iii) true, Cl 4.4.6.1 ,p 60 \n iv) not true"
    }
  ]
}
